<!-- contents for the index page -->
<xml>
 <section section_id="Waterston"> 
  <![CDATA[
<h3>Global Identification of Transcribed Regions of the <i>C. elegans</i> Genome</h3>
<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Robert Waterston (PI)<br>
Mark Gerstein<br>
Philip Green<br>
Michael MacCoss<br>
David Miller<br>
Valerie Reinke<br>
Frank Slack
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
University of Washington<br>
Yale University<br>
University of Washington<br>
University of Washington<br>
Vanderbilt University<br>
Yale University<br>
Yale University
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Waterston"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>
Despite the complexity of the challenge, the goal of this proposal is to approach a complete description of the transcribed genome, 
classified where possible by function such as likely acting as an RNA or protein. Where we cannot definitively classify a sequence, 
we expect to provide estimates of the likelihood of its function.  We will combine all existing data for protein coding genes with gene models from GeneFinder, Twinscan and the current WormBase to define a set of confirmed exon-intron junctions and combine these into complete coding genes with their alternative splice forms. This thorough reannotation of the genome alone will move beyond the current WormBase gene set both by incorporating additional available data, including the emerging genome sequences of related nematodes, and by examining all the datasets across the entire genome.
<p>
We will in turn test predicted but unconfirmed exons including UTRs and their intron junctions by specific RT-PCR and RACE and sequence analysis of the products.
<p>
We will seek to find new evidence for transcribed regions, exploiting the recently commercially available genome tiling arrays for C. elegans. To maximize the chances for discovering stage and cell specific transcripts, we will use carefully staged populations, mutants lacking or overproducing certain cell types, purified embryonic cell populations and mRNA populations purified from specific post-embryonic cell types.
<p>
These data will in turn be added to existing data sets along with any other data emerging from the community to suggest additional gene models for both protein coding and non-coding transcripts. Again these results will guide further RT-PCR and RACE experiments. We expect these data will also be particularly valuable for suggesting previously undefined 5 and 3 prime UTRs.
<p>
Finally we will look for evidence of translation of small open reading frames from either single exon genes or spliced transcripts using mass-spectrometry. The overall result should be a usefully comprehensive set of transcripts, cataloged into protein-coding and non-coding RNAs that will aid in the identification of other functional elements in the worm genome as well as provide a resource for broader explorations of gene function in this incomparable worm.

  ]]>
 </section>
 
 <section section_id="Introduction">
  <![CDATA[
<p>The National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI) model organism
ENCODE (modENCODE) Project will try to identify all of the
sequence-based functional elements in the 
<i>Caenorhabditis elegans
</i> and 
<i>Drosophila melanogaster
</i> genomes.  The project is run as a Research Network. 
<br>
</p>

<p>See NHGRI 
<a href="http://www.genome.gov/25521166/">news release
</a>, and background information about the project can be found in the two RFAs.
<a href="http://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/rfa-files/RFA-HG-06-006.html" class="external text" title="http://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/rfa-files/RFA-HG-06-006.html" rel="nofollow">
RFA-HG-06-006
</a>
solicits applications for a set of projects that will conduct
experiments to identify functional elements in the target genomes. 
<a href="http://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/rfa-files/RFA-HG-06-007.html" class="external text" title="http://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/rfa-files/RFA-HG-06-007.html" rel="nofollow">
RFA-HG-06-007
</a> solicits applications to participate in the Research Network as a Data Coordination Center.
</p> 
<p>More information will appear on this site over the coming months. Please check back for descriptions of the projects, experimental protocols, and released data sets.

<br>
</p>

Please contact <a href="mailto:help@modencode.org">help@modencode.org</a> for more information.

  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Genomes">
  <![CDATA[

<iframe width=100% height=100% frameborder=0 src="http://www.modencode.org/karyotypes.html">
</iframe>

      ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Lieb">
  <![CDATA[
 <h3>Identification of DNA Elements Governing Chromatin Function in <i>C. elegan</i>s</h3>

<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Jason Lieb (PI)<br>
Julie Ahringer<br>
Abby Dernberg<br>
Arshad Desai<br>
Roland Green<br>
Xiole Liu Eran Segal<br>
Susan Strome
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill<br>
University of Cambridge<br>
University of California, Berkeley<br>
University of California, San Diego<br>
NimbleGen Dana Farber Cancer Institute<br>
Weizmann Institute <br>
Indiana University, Bloomington
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Lieb"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>

Eukaryotic genomes are packaged into chromatin, which regulates the function of proteins that mediate transcriptional activity and other essential processes, including recombination and the faithful segregation of the genome during mitosis and meiosis. The goal of this proposal is to identify discrete elements that regulate chromatin structure and function in the nematode <i>C. elegans</i>, a model metazoan of central importance in large-scale genomic research and gene function discovery. We will first use ChIP-chip and related methods to map the genomic distributions of selected histone modifications and chromosome-associated proteins, and then use that information, in combination with data from other modENCODE groups, to build quantitative models of chromatin function. Specifically, we will:

1. Identify and technically validate functional elements that control chromatin and chromosome behavior.The focus of our analysis will be elements that specify nucleosome positioning and occupancy, control domains of gene expression, induce repression of the X chromosome, guide mitotic segregation and genome duplication, govern homolog pairing and recombination during meiosis, and organize chromosome positioning within the nucleus. 126 strategically selected targets include key histone modifications, histone variants, RNA polymerase II isoforms, dosage-compensation proteins, centromere components, homolog-pairing facilitators, recombination markers, and nuclear-envelope constituents. An efficient pipeline design will facilitate identification and validation of the different classes of functional elements associated with these targets and integrate the results with the well-annotated C. elegans genome.

2. Biologically validate identified functional elements and build integrated, quantitative models of chromo-some function.We will integrate information generated in Aim 1 with existing knowledge on the biology of the targets, perform ChIP-chip analysis on mutant and RNAi extracts lacking selected target proteins, use extrachromosomal arrays to assess the ability of candidate identified sequence motifs to recruit targets in vivo, identify tissue-specific patterns of selected targets, and create integrated, quantitative models of transcription and whole-chromosome functions.

Achieving these goals in the context of the ongoing expansion and rich history of C. elegans research will provide an important milestone in meeting the challenge of using genome sequence information to understand and predict biological functions. 
  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Henikoff">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>Genome-wide profiling of histone variants in <i>Drosophila</i> and <i>Caenorhabditis</i></h3>
<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Steven Henikoff (PI)<br>
Kamran Ahmad
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center<br>
Harvard University
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Henikoff"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>
We will map major core histone variants throughout the annotated <i>Drosophila melanogaster</i> and <i>Caenorhabditis</i> elegans genomes at high resolution. These maps will provide a chromatin-based framework for interpreting epigenetic information and gene expression patterns determined by others.

To accomplish this, we will use the biotin-tagging system that we have successfully applied for genome-scale chromatin affinity purification together with a standard microarray readout platform. In both <i>D. melanogaster</i> and C. elegans we will profile the universal replication-independent histone 3 variant, H3.3, as well as the control replication-coupled variant, H3. These data will provide high-resolution genome-wide maps of histone dynamics in both model organisms.

The close correspondences of H3.3 patterns to patterns of active histone modifications genome-wide and with DNaseI hypersensitive sites at homeotic gene clusters suggests that our genome-wide maps can be used to validate efforts aimed at mapping these other genomic features.

In both <i>D. melanogaster</i> and C. elegans we will also profile the H2AZ variant, which has been linked to epigenetic processes in a variety of different organisms. <I>Drosophila</I> H2AZ plays a unique dual role as the H2AX variant, called H2AV, and our preliminary studies indicate that patterns of H2AV differ from those of H3.3, thus providing a different epigenetic profile of histone dynamics genome-wide.

To expand our understanding of the functional roles of both classes of histone variants, we will use RNAi to knock down the function of key chromatin regulators in Drosophila cell lines and in whole C. elegans at different developmental stages. Transcriptional profiling after knock-down of the variants and their assembly machines will provide functional validation of roles that they play in gene regulation, and histone variant profiling after knock-down should help to identify target genes.

Together with other types of genome-wide information our histone variant maps are likely to contribute to a fuller understanding of epigenetic regulatory elements in the genomes of these two model organisms. Given that the same histone variants are thought to play similar roles in essentially all complex eukaryotes, our basic approach can be immediately applied to the human genome. 
  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Snyder">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>Identification of Transcription Factor Binding Regions</h3>
<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Michael Snyder (PI)<br>
Mark Gerstein<br>
Anthony Hyman<br>
Stuart Kim<br> 
Valerie Reinke<br>
Robert Waterston
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
Yale University<br>
Yale University<br>
Max Planck Institute<br>
Stanford University<br> 
Yale University<br>
University of Washington
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Snyder"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>

<i>C. elegans</i> has a modest-sized and completely sequenced genome, a completely defined somatic cell lineage, and a small number of cells; thus it provides an ideal system to map the regulatory information encoded in its genome. We propose to identify the DNA binding sites for 300 transcription factors in C. elegans. Transcription factor genes will be tagged and their expression examined throughout the C. elegans life cycle. The binding sites of each factor will be determined using chromatin immunoprecipitation followed by DNA microarray analysis (ChIP-chip). This binding information will be compared to other genome annotation and made publicly available. Specifically, we will: 1) Prepare constructs in which all transcription factor genes are fused to coding sequences for fluorescent reporter genes. (Hyman) 2) Generate a series of C. elegans lines that express each fusion construct and obtain a preliminary evaluation of the temporal and spatial expression of each factor throughout the life cycle of the animal. (Waterston, Kim) 3) Based on the expression results, perform ChIP-chip of each factor at one or more key time points. (Snyder, Reinke) 4) Validate the binding results using quantitative measures to measure binding. (Snyder, Reinke). 5) Implement high-throughput data processing pipelines and store the results of these in a web-accessible database for use by the scientific community. (Gerstein) 6) Perform a limited number of bioinformatic analyses to identify regulatory motifs, analyze the association of binding sites between factors and their distribution in the genome (Gerstein) We expect this project to contribute significant information to the identification of regulatory elements in the C. elegans genome; additionally it will serve as a model for parallel studies in human systems.
  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Piano">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>Encyclopedia of <i>C. elegans</i> 3&#39; UTRs and their regulatory elements</h3>

<table class=PI>
<td width=250>
<b>
Fabio Piano (PI)<br>
Kristin Gunsalus<br> 
John Kim<br>
Nikolaus Rajewsky 
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
New York University<br>
New York University<br> 
University of Michigan<br>
New York University
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Piano"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>
The 3&#39; untranslated region (3&#39; UTR) constitutes a major site of post-transcriptional regulation of gene expression. Sequence elements in the 3&#39;UTR interact with trans-acting regulators such as microRNAs that affect translation and stability. Deciphering the global interactions among these sequence elements will open a new window into gene regulatory networks. However, mapping these interactions in vivo will require detailed cell- or tissue-type specific data as well as new methods for in vivo validation studies. To obtain molecular resolution of these sequence elements in a living organism at a genomic scale, we need to develop and implement new methods and explore their use for large-scale analyses. We are thus proposing to conduct a pilot project toward building a comprehensive dynamic view of the &quote;3&#39; UTRome&quote; in the context of animal development in the model organism <i>C. elegans</i>. Our overall aims are to: 1. Pilot a 3&#39;RACE-cloning-sequencing strategy to identify the 3&#39;UTRs of ~6,000 transcripts and explore their heterogeneity. 2. Pilot new technology to map temporal and tissue-specific profiles of small RNAs and mRNAs in <i>C. elegans</i>. 3. Pilot an in vivo system to test elements that mediate post-transcriptional regulation of gene expression.

  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Celniker">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>Comprehensive characterization of the <i>Drosophila</i> transcriptome</h3>

<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Susan Celniker (PI)<br>
Michael Brent<br>
Steven Brenner<br>
Peter Cherbas<br>
Thomas Gingeras<br>
Brenton Gravely<br>
Roger Hoskins 
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory<br>
Washington University<br>
University of California, Berkeley<br>
Indiana University<br>
Affymetrix<br>
University of Connecticut Health Systems<br> 
Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Celniker"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>


This proposal responds to the modENCODE RFA to identify all of the sequence-based functional elements associated with transcribed sequences &quote;including both protein coding and non-protein coding sequences, specifically characterizing gene structures including transcription start sites (TSS), polyadenylation sites, and alternative transcripts in <I>Drosophila</I>&quote;. We propose to generate a comprehensive set of developmentally staged and tissue- and cell-specific RNAs for expression profiling using high-density genome tiling microarrays and 454 pyrosequencing of small RNAs. These expression data will be used for sophisticated transcript modeling that integrates extant EST and cDNA sequence and comparative data from the 12 sequenced Drosophila genomes. The models will serve as the foundation for experimental validation by sequencing of cDNA and RTPCR products, RACE to define TSSs, and for small non-protein coding RNAs (ncRNAs), by functional validation in RNAi assays. The experimental validation data will be incorporated into the informatics pipeline to produce improved transcript models. In our final product, these models will include comprehensive annotations of TSSs, exon/intron structures, polyadenylation sites and the cis-elements required for splicing. We have assembled a project management team to obtain the necessary infrastructure and expertise to complete the goals of the proposal. The managers and their roles and responsibilities are: Peter Cherbas (IU), RNA samples and evaluation of computational models; Thomas Gingeras (Affymetrix), microarray expression profiling and analysis; Michael Brent (WUSTL), data integration and transcript modeling; Roger Hoskins (LBNL), sequence-based validation; Brenton Graveley (UCHC), alternate splicing; and Norbert Perrimon (Harvard), function of ncRNAs.

  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="White">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>Identification of Transcription Factor binding sites by high-throughput ChIP-chip experiments in <i>Drosophila</i></h3>

<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Kevin White (PI)<br>
Hugo Bellen<br>
Martha Bulyk<br>
Frank Collart<br> 
Roger Haskins<br>
Manolis Kellis<br>
James Posakony<br>
Bing Ren<br>
Steven Russell<br>
Robert White
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
University of Chicago<br>
Baylor College of Medicine<br>
Brigham and Women&#39;s Hospital<br>
Argonne National Lab<br>
Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory<br>
Massachusetts Institute of Technology<br>
University of California, San Diego<br>
Ludwig Institute<br>
University of Cambridge University of Cambridge
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/White"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>

The White Lab is aiming to map the association of all the <i>Drosophila</i> Transcription Factors (TF) and DNA associated proteins on the fly's whole genome. The main technique that will be used for this purpose is ChIP-chip.

To achieve this goal, we designed a multi-step pipeline starting from the comprehensive listing of the fly TF to the classification of cis-regulatory modules (CRM). The steps of this pipeline are described in the figure below. The Module 1 aims to produce ChIP-grade antibodies for every TF in the fly genome. After thorough validation these antibodies will be used for the ChIP experiments performed in the Module 2. The ChIP samples produced will then be used to hybridize whole-genome tiling microarays. The data generated by ChIP-chip experiments consist basically of a plot of signal intensity across the genome. The highest signals correspond to positions in the genome occupied by the tested TF. The Module 3 aims to identify these binding sites, to classify them and to extract biological information by extensive comparaison between the different datasets. Also developed in the computational part of the pipeline is a tracking database called DSTN to help in coordination of the different persons involved in the pipeline.
  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Karpen">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>Genome-Wide Mapping of Chromosomal Proteins in <i>Drosophilia</i></h3>
<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Gary Karpen (PI)<br>
Sarah Elgin<br>
Mitzi Kuroda<br> 
Peter Park<br>
Vincent Pirrotta<br>
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory<br>
Washington University<br> 
Brigham and Women&#39;s Hospital<br>
Brigham and Women&#39;s Hospital<br> 
Rutgers University
</td>
<td width=200 align=right>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Karpen"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>
 The packaging of DNA into chromatin and chromosomes has major implications for understanding how genome sequences function in eukaryotic cells. We propose to participate in the ENCODE project by determining the locations of 125 chromosomal proteins and histone modifications across the Drosophila melanogaster genome. The proteins and modifications under study are involved in basic chromosomal functions such as DNA replication, gene expression, gene silencing, and inheritance. We will perform Chromatin ImmunoPrecipitation (ChIP) with antibodies obtained commercially and generated and validated by this project, isolate and label the precipitated DNA, and apply the probes to genomic tiling arrays. Data generated by scanning the hybridized arrays will be analyzed by statistical methods, and the array data will be validated by independent analyses in cells and animals. We will initially assay localizations using chromatin from three cell lines and two embryonic stages, and will then extend the analysis of a subset of proteins to four additional animal tissues/stages. We will perform a variety of bioinformatic comparisons between protein &quote;landscape&quote; data sets, including analyses of combinatorial patterns of modifications and chromosomal proteins, tissue-specific differences, and interactions among proteins involved in the same epigenetic pathways. All validated data and analyses will be made available to members of the ENCODE project and the scientific community. Successful completion of this project will provide basic information about the distributions of chromatin components across the Drosophila genome, which will serve as a foundation for future functional studies. The data and analysis are very likely to provide information critical to understanding the roles of chromatin packaging in human cells, and the mispackaging that can be associated with disease.

  ]]>
</section>

 <section section_id="Lai">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>Annotation of the small RNA/microRNA component of the <i>Drosophila</i> genome</h3>

<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Eric Lai (PI)<br>
Gregory Hannon
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
Sloan-Kettering Institute<br>
Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Lai"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>

We plan to generate a comprehensive catalog of expressed and functional microRNAs, and generate biological evidence for their regulatory activity. We plan also to delineate the primary transcription units of microRNA genes. Finally, we plan to annotate other classes of non-miRNA expressed small RNAs, as least some of which may define novel classes of small RNA genes. 
  ]]>
</section>

 <section section_id="MacAlpine">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>The Systematic Identification and Analysis of Replication Origins in <i>Drosophila</i></h3>
<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
David MacAlpine (PI)<br>
Terry Orr-Weaver
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
Duke University<br>
Whitehead Institute
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/MacAlpine"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>

We will use high-density genomic tiling-path arrays to characterize the Drosophila replication program in multiple cell lines and tissues. Specifically, we will determine the time of replication for all unique sequences in the Drosophila genome, identify and map all functional origins of replication, and identify all sites of pre-replicative complex (preRC) assembly. The high-resolution mapping of sites of preRC assembly will enable us to apply computational approaches (including comparative genomics) to identify potential sequence motifs that direct and regulate preRC function. Finally, we will also characterize the differential replication of polytene chromosomes in fully differentiated Drosophila tissues to identify genomic regions that are amplified or underreplicated. 
  ]]>
</section>

 <section section_id="Stein">
  <![CDATA[
<h3>A Data Coordinating Center for modENCODE</h3>
<table class=PI>
<tr>
<td width=250>
<b>
Lincoln Stein (PI)<br>
James Kent<br> 
Suzanna Lewis<br>
Gos Micklem 
</b>
</td>
<td width=325>
Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory<br>
University of California, Santa Cruz<br> 
Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory<br>
University of Cambridge
</td>
<td width=200 align=right><br>
<a href="http://wiki.modencode.org/index.php/Stein"
   onmouseover="balloon.showTooltip(event,'Jump to a  more detailed description of this research project on the modENCODE Wiki')">
Details...
</a>
</td></tr></table>
<hr>

<h4>Project Objectives</h4>
This is the data coordinating center (DCC) for the project. Our role is to track the data, integrate it with other information sources, and make it available to the research community in a timely and open fashion.

<h4>Experimental Approaches</h4>
We will assemble a team of three data managers stationed at CSHL and at Berkeley, who have a background in the bioinformatics of C. elegans and/or D. melanogaster. The managers will liaise with their contacts at the data provider sites to determine data file formats, milestones and quality control procedures for their datasets. They will also liaise with representatives from NCBI to coordinate modENCODE activities with the primary data repositories at GenBank and GEO.

Data providers will upload their data sets to a staging server where they will be able to preview their data on an instance of the GBrowse genome browser. The data managers will QC the data before approving its transfer to the production database. Data will be integrated in the production database using InterMine, and from there released to the public on a monthly schedule. Researchers will be able to access the data via the GBrowse genome browser, bulk downloads, and via complex queries and reports mediated by InterMine and the BioMart data warehousing system. All major software systems used by the proposed DCC will be based on open source tools from the Generic Model Organism Database (GMOD) , human ENCODE, and other sources.

Throughout the project, Lewis and Stein will work close with FlyBase and/or WormBase to ensure that data collected by modENCODE becomes an integral part of the relevant model organism database. In addition we will dedicate a significant part of a data manager&#39;s effort to transfer data from modENCODE into the MODs during the last year of the project.

]]>
 </section>


 <section section_id="WIKI">
  <![CDATA[
<a href="http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/a/network/2006/07/07/what-is-a-wiki.html" target="_new">What is a Wiki?</a>
<br>

<h3 class=subSection>The modENCODE Wiki</h3>
&#8226; Contains detailed information about the research projects, experimental protocols, reagents, 
resources etc..<br>
&#8226; The modencode Wiki is public and can be accessed by anyone.<br>
&#8226; Account holders in project labs are able to update the Wiki contents directly.
<p>
<table><tr valign=middle>
<td>
<a href="mailto:help@modencode.org?subject=Public Wiki" title="help@modencode.org">
<img src="/img/email.png" height=25 border=0 align=top></a>
</td>
<td>
<a href="mailto:help@modencode.org?subject=Public Wiki" title="help@modencode.org"> &nbsp;Wiki help/questions</a>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a target="_new" href="http://wiki.modencode.org" title="wiki.modencode.org">
<img src="/img/green_arrow.png" width=40 border=0></a></td>
<td>
<a target="_new" href="http://wiki.modencode.org" title="wiki.modencode.org"> &nbsp;Go to the modencode Wiki</a>
</td>
</tr>
</table>
</p>

<br><br>

<h3 class=subSection>The Project Wiki (restricted access)</h3>
&#8226; This is a seperate, private wiki for communication between modENCODE projects and the data coordination center.
<br>
&#8226; Access is restricted to modENCODE lab members and other interested parties.
<p>
  
<table>
<tr valign=middle>
<td>
<a href="mailto:help@modencode.org?subject=Private Wiki account" title="help@modencode.org">
<img src="/img/email.png" height=25 border=0 align=top></a>
</td>
<td>
<a href="mailto:help@modencode.org?subject=Private Wiki account" title="help@modencode.org">
 &nbsp;Request an account
</a>
</td>
</a>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a target="_new" href="http://wiki.modencode.org/project" title="wiki.modencode.org/project">
<img src="/img/green_arrow.png" width=40 border=0></a></td>
<td>
<a target="_new" href="http://wiki.modencode.org/project" title="wiki.modencode.org/project">
 &nbsp;Go to the project Wiki</a></td>
</tr>
</table>
</p>

  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="Contact">
  <![CDATA[
  <h3>modENCODE Data Coordination Center</h3>

<table cellpadding=5 width=100%>
<tr>
<th colspan=2 style="padding-left:50px;text-align:left;background-color:lightsteelblue">
<b>Principal Investigators</b>
</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width=30><a href="mailto:lstein@cshl.edu" title="lstein@cshl.edu">
<img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Lincoln Stein</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align=left><a href="mailto:suzi@fruitfly.org" title="suzi@fruitfly.org">
<img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Suzi Lewis (coPI)</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align=left><a href="mailto:kent@soe.ucsc.edu" title="kent@soe.ucsc.edu">
<img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Jim Kent (coPI)</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align=left><a href="mailto:gos@gen.cam.ac.uk"><img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Gos Micklem (coPI)</td>
</tr>

<tr><td colspan=2>&nbsp;</td></tr>

<tr>
<th colspan=2 style="padding-left:50px;text-align:left;background-color:lightsteelblue">
<b>Data Managers</b>
</th>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align=left><a href="mailto:NLWashington@lbl.gov" title="NLWashington@lbl.gov"><img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Nicole Washinton (<i>D. melanogaster</i>)</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align=left><a href="mailto:mckays@cshl.edu" title="mckays@cshl.edu"><img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Sheldon McKay (<i>C. elegans</i>)</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align=left><a href="mailto:zha@cshl.edu" title="zha@cshl.edu"><img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Zheng Zha (<i>C. elegans</i>)</td>
</tr>

<tr><td colspan=2>&nbsp;</td></tr>

<tr>
<th colspan=2 style="padding-left:50px;text-align:left;background-color:lightsteelblue">
<b>Web Site</b>
</th>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align=left><a href="mailto:mckays@cshl.edu" title="mckays@cshl.edu"><img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Sheldon McKay (web site/wiki)</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align=left><a href="mailto:francois@flymine.org" title="francois@flymine.org"><img src="/img/email.png" height=20 border=0 align=top></a></td>
<td>Fran&#231;ois Guillier (systems)</td>
</tr>

</table>

  ]]>
 </section>

 <section section_id="">                                                                                                                             
  <![CDATA[                                                                                                                                          
                                                                                                                                                     
  ]]>                                                                                                                                                
 </section> 
 <section section_id="">                                                                                                                             
  <![CDATA[                                                                                                                                          
                                                                                                                                                     
  ]]>                                                                                                                                                
 </section> 

</xml>
